<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on José Devezas, PhD</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on José Devezas, PhD</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2021 José Devezas</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 11:17:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Searching through a git repository</title>
      <link>/blog/searching_git/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 11:17:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/searching_git/</guid>
      <description>Log search Finding a log with a certain string in the commit message:
git log --grep=query Content search Finding a commit where a given string was introduced in the code:
git log -Squery Same as the previous, but using a regex instead of string matching:
git log -Gquery Word difference comparison Running a diff based on words rather than lines (useful when managing a blog, documentation, or scientific writing in LaTeX):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/academy/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 16:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/academy/projects/</guid>
      <description>Army ANT FeedArchive ANT Juggle Juggle Mobile Breadcrumbs Ciclope                              Army ANT Army ANT is an information retrieval research framework that supports experimentation with classical approaches, while also providing a high-level abstraction that motivates the implementation of innovative approaches in a shared evaluation environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/academy/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 22:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/academy/publications/</guid>
      <description>Journals Conferences Datasets Theses Chapters Reports Unpublished  Journals Devezas, José, and Sérgio Nunes. &amp;ldquo;Characterizing the Hypergraph-of-Entity and the Structural Impact of Its Extensions&amp;rdquo;. Applied Network Science - Special Issue of the 8th International Conference on Complex Networks and Their Applications 5.1 (2020): 79   Devezas, José, and Sérgio Nunes. &amp;ldquo;Hypergraph-of-Entity: A Unified Representation Model for the Retrieval of Text and Knowledge&amp;rdquo;. Open Computer Science 9.1 (2019): 103-127   Devezas, José, and Sérgio Nunes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posters</title>
      <link>/academy/posters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 18:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/academy/posters/</guid>
      <description>          </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demos</title>
      <link>/academy/demos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 18:58:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/academy/demos/</guid>
      <description>    Your browser does not support the video tag, but check out FourEyes website instead. 
     </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides</title>
      <link>/academy/slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 17:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/academy/slides/</guid>
      <description> Talks  Conferences Invited speaker   Lectures  Invited assistant  GIRS 2017/2018   Invited speaker  ASSO 2019/2020 DAPI 2018/2019     Theses  Doctoral Master&amp;rsquo;s    Talks Conferences            Invited speaker           Lectures Invited assistant GIRS 2017/2018               Invited speaker ASSO 2019/2020   DAPI 2018/2019       Theses Doctoral   Master&amp;rsquo;s   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>A creative, classical liberal, PhD in Computer Science from Portugal. Specialist in information retrieval and network science. Enjoys random walks, machine learning, and data science. Mainly codes in Python, but also a master of R, and a lover of Scala. Believer in diversity and equality, but not fussy about it. No-bullshit, people-take-precedence policy, and an endless passion for questioning. Gets bored easily, works best when focused on a single, challenging goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Career</title>
      <link>/career/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/career/</guid>
      <description>I have been doing research since 2009, where I began at SAPO Labs/U.Porto with information retrieval work on blog search and link analysis. In 2010, I finished my Master&amp;rsquo;s in Informatics and Computing Engineering, at the Faculty of Engineering of the University of Porto.
I continued at SAPO Labs, working on data visualization and link analysis for a while, and then I moved to CRACS/INESC TEC, at the Faculty of Sciences of the University of Porto.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>Address
Faculty of Engineering, University of Porto,
Rua Dr. Roberto Frias s/n, 4200-465 Porto, Portugal
E-mail
joseluisdevezas@gmail.com
Twitter
@jldevezas
LinkedIn
https://pt.linkedin.com/in/jldevezas
GitHub
https://github.com/jldevezas/</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
